MacKaye Family papers ML-5
Rauner Special Collections Library
- Addendum 1, 1861-1953|; 22
  - Box: 268, 1868-1951 (Box 268)
    - Percy MacKaye: Writing: The Oldest Man In The World", undated (Box 268, Folder 52)
    - Percy MacKaye: Inventory List of Percy MacKaye's Work", undated (Box 268, Folder 53)
    - Hazel MacKaye: Writing: Notes, 1942 (Box 268, Folder 54)
    - Hazel MacKaye: Correspondence, 1942 (Box 268, Folder 55)
    - Percy MacKaye: Writing; Original MS for "Gossip - A Comedy Sketch", undated (Box 268, Folder 56)
    - Percy MacKaye: Writing: Original MS for "A Philosophers's Fool", undated (Box 268, Folder 57)
  - Hazel MacKaye: Correspondence, 1936-1942 (Box 269)
    Hazel MacKaye: Correspondence
  - Contains Clay Relief of Col. MacKaye, Photographs of Percy MacKaye, Glass Photoplate of Ms. Clar..., 1880's-1920's (Box 270)
    Contains Clay Relief of Col. MacKaye, Photographs of Percy MacKaye, Glass Photoplate of Ms. Clara Parker, Stage Photographs of Steele MacKaye, Framed Notes on the Dialect of Southern Mountaineers by Steele MacKaye, Script for "Washington" by Percy MacKaye
  - Contains William Payson MacKaye's Sketchbook, Percy MacKaye's Photographs and Theatre Flyers, 1919-1945 (Box 271)
    Contains William Payson MacKaye's Sketchbook, Percy MacKaye's Photographs and Theatre Flyers
  - Box: 272, 1856-1950's (Box 272)
    Box: 272
    - Percy MacKaye: Writings, undated (Box 272, Folder 1)
    - Percy MacKaye: Correspondence, 1940's-1950's (Box 272, Folder 2)
    - Percy MacKaye: Writing: "Poog's Pasture", undated (Box 272, Folder 3)
    - Arvia MacKaye: Miscellaneous on Anthroposoohy, 1939 (Box 272, Folder 4)
    - Percy MacKaye: Correspondence, 1930's (Box 272, Folder 5)
    - Percy MacKaye: Correspondence from Benton MacKaye, 1930's (Box 272, Folder 6)
    - Percy MacKaye: Correspondence, 1930's (Box 272, Folder 7)
    - Percy MacKaye: Correspondence, 1930's (Box 272, Folder 8)
    - Percy MacKaye: Correspondence from Hazel MacKaye, 1940's (Box 272, Folder 9)
    - Percy MacKaye: Miscellaneous items related to Marion Morse Mackay's Illness and Death in Switzerland, 1939 (Box 272, Folder 10)
    - Percy MacKaye: Photographs of Shirley, Mass. And others, undated (Box 272, Folder 11)
    - Percy MacKaye: Newspaper Clippings, Miscellaneous Items and Ephemera, 1930's (Box 272, Folder 12)
    - Percy MacKaye: Notebooks on Pageant and Masques of St.Louis, 1924 (Box 272, Folder 13)
    - Percy MacKaye: Woodblock Print of Steelee MacKaye, 1927 (Box 272, Folder 14)
    - Percy MacKaye: Miscellaneous Items, undated (Box 272, Folder 15)
    - Percy MacKaye: Miscellaneous Items, Newspaper Clippings and Correspondence, 1930's (Box 272, Folder 16)
    - William Payson MacKaye: Writing: "Expressionn Of The Arms," "Evolution Of Expression," "Organization Of The Arm," "Spiral Radiation On Gesticulation", 1856-1886 (Box 272, Folder 17)
  - Box: 273, 1877-1942 (Box 273)
    Box: 273
    - Hazel MacKaye: Writing: "Notes On The Purpose Of Creation", 1942 (Box 273, Folder 1)
    - Percy MacKaye: Writing: "The Sainted Cow - A Legend", undated (Box 273, Folder 2)
    - Percy MacKaye: E.A. Robinson, 1934-1935 (Box 273, Folder 3)
    - Percy MacKaye: Copies of Letters from E.A.Robinson, 1907-1928 (Box 273, Folder 4)
    - Percy MacKaye: Miscelaneous Items relating to "Annals Of An Era", 1930's (Box 273, Folder 5)
    - Percy MacKaye: Writing: Various Uncollected Poems Bound 1897-1924, 1940 (Box 273, Folder 6)
    - Percy MacKaye: Writing: Original Unnamed MS, 1933-1934 (Box 273, Folder 7)
    - Percy MacKaye: items related to "Old Fort Niagara", 19030's (Box 273, Folder 8)
    - Percy MacKaye: Writing: Miscellaneous Poems, undated (Box 273, Folder 9)
    - Percy MacKaye: Writing: Miscellaneous Published Poems, undated (Box 273, Folder 10)
    - Steele MacKaye: Pamphlets and Ephemera On Acting, 1877-1934 (Box 273, Folder 11)
    - Percy MacKaye: Writing: "Life", 1921-1922 (Box 273, Folder 12)
    - Mary Medbery MacKaye: Writing: "Haps Redivius-A Page From The Story Of The Evolution Of A French Creation", 1908 (Box 273, Folder 13)
    - Percy MacKaye: Writing: Unidentified Play, undated (Box 273, Folder 14)
    - Percy Mackey: Dartmouth College Press Proofs for "Annals Of An Era", 1930's (Box 273, Folder 15)
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains copy of "To-morrow: A Play by Percy MacKaye"; a copy of "Johnny Crimson..., 1890's-1950's (Box 274)
    Percy MacKaye: Contains copy of "To-morrow: A Play by Percy MacKaye"; a copy of "Johnny Crimson: A Legend of Hollis Hall"; several typed copies with handwritten notes of "The Canterbury Pilgrims: An Opera by Percy MacKaye"; miscellaneous handwritten and typed notes; personal and professional correspondence; copy of "The Gobbler of God: A Poem of the Southern Appalachians"; newspaper clippings; theatre and literature pamphlets, notes regarding the works of Percy MacKaye
  - Contains programs and pamphlets for various productions; miscellaneous notes and writings; perso..., 1890's-1950's (Box 275)
    Contains programs and pamphlets for various productions; miscellaneous notes and writings; personal and professional correspondence; newspaper clippings and Journals (1911 and 1912) related to Percy MacKaye
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains a copy of "Percy MacKaye 50th Birthday Symposium"; newspaper clippings; ..., 1890's-1950's (Box 276)
    Percy MacKaye: Contains a copy of "Percy MacKaye 50th Birthday Symposium"; newspaper clippings; a folder containing clippings and other pamphlets pertaining to Marion Morse MacKaye; dozens of miscellaneous theatre programs and literature pamphlets; a copy of "Hamlet: King of Denmark"; miscellaneous writings including "Skippers of Nancy Gloucester"
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains handwritten and typed notes; several literary pamphlets; programs; noteb..., 1890's-1950's (Box 277)
    Percy MacKaye: Contains handwritten and typed notes; several literary pamphlets; programs; notebooks; a 50th anniversary book for MacKaye's Harvard graduating class; newspapers and clippings; folders of personal and professional correspondence, including writer Howard Fast
  - Percy MacKaye: Several literary publications, reviews, and pamphlets; boxes of letters and misce..., 1890's-1950's (Box 278)
    Percy MacKaye: Several literary publications, reviews, and pamphlets; boxes of letters and miscellaneous writings
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains literary publications; a folder with professional correspondence and not..., 1890's-1950' (Box 279)
    Percy MacKaye: Contains literary publications; a folder with professional correspondence and notes for "Annals of an Era"; personal and professional correspondence; miscellaneous writings
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains several literary publications and pamphlets; newspaper clippings; writi..., 1890's-1950's (Box 280)
    Percy MacKaye: Contains several literary publications and pamphlets; newspaper clippings; writings entitled "Moments in Voyage"; notes regarding "Dogtown Common"; a folder of correspondence entitled "Literary and Historical Records: 1903-1930" with several notable correspondents such as Lady Gregory, James Bryce, Robert Frost, Theodore Roosevelt, Eugene O' Neil, Booth Tarkington, JB Yeats, Charles W. Eliot, among others; a copy of "Survey Graphic"; financial papers
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains newspaper clippings; photographs; notes; receipts; correspondence; a cop..., 1890's-1950's (Box 281)
    Percy MacKaye: Contains newspaper clippings; photographs; notes; receipts; correspondence; a copy of "Brave Enterprise" by A.K. Chesterson; and a program from the Shakespeare Memorial Theatre in 1932
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains biographical and bibliographical materials for MacKaye's works; miscella..., 1890's-1950's (Box 282)
    Percy MacKaye: Contains biographical and bibliographical materials for MacKaye's works; miscellaneous notes and correspondence
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains loose manuscripts; MacKaye's high school sketch notebook; miscellaneous ..., 1890's-1950's (Box 283)
    Percy MacKaye: Contains loose manuscripts; MacKaye's high school sketch notebook; miscellaneous papers and notes; financial papers; several editions of his own publications; dozens of literary publications and pamphlets; periodical and newspaper clippings; hardcover edition of MacKaye's "Weathergoose-Woo!; MacKaye's "Poem-Leaflets" and "The Evergreen Tree"
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains notebook of typed and handwritten poetry and notes; a copper printing pl..., 1890's-1950's (Box 284)
    Percy MacKaye: Contains notebook of typed and handwritten poetry and notes; a copper printing plate; receipts; newspaper clippings; photographs
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains brown leather note/address book; "Services in Remberance of Marion Morse..., 1890's-1950's (Box 285)
    Percy MacKaye: Contains brown leather note/address book; "Services in Remberance of Marion Morse MacKaye"; personal correspondence; photographs; glass negatives; copy of "The Communal Drama"; miscellaneous notes, notebooks, writings
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains glass-plate negative; newspaper clippings and notebooks; a folder enti..., 1890's-1950's (Box 286)
    Percy MacKaye: Contains glass-plate negative; newspaper clippings and notebooks; a folder entitled "Mountain Material"; several literary periodicals; photographs; personal correspondence; the ‘Lost green journal' of Marion MacKaye, 1937-38
  - Contains a long rolled photograph of the Reunion class of 1897 from Harvard; personal correspond..., 1890's-1950's (Box 287)
    Contains a long rolled photograph of the Reunion class of 1897 from Harvard; personal correspondence of Percy MacKaye; a notebook of poems by Nancy MacKaye; notebooks of poems by Christy, Jean, and Arvia MacKaye; several literary periodicals
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains a certificate from the Madison Square Theatre; diploma from Harvard; han..., 1890's-1950's (Box 288)
    Percy MacKaye: Contains a certificate from the Madison Square Theatre; diploma from Harvard; handwritten letters in the style of a medieval manuscript; photographs; copies of sketches; a copy of "The Century"
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains a set of schedules entitled "The Caliban Time Table Chart", 1890's-1950's (Box 289)
    Percy MacKaye: Contains a set of schedules entitled "The Caliban Time Table Chart"
  - Mary L. MacKaye Weiss: Contains a diary with photographs concerning travels in Egypt and Europe;..., 1894-1960 (Box 290)
    Mary L. MacKaye Weiss: Contains a diary with photographs concerning travels in Egypt and Europe; January, 1950 issue of "Proceedings of the New Jersey Historical Society"; a scrap book in a series titled "Family Lore: The Trooks and The MacKayes" including newspaper clippings, illustrations, photographs and memoires; scrap books in an autobiographical series on Mary MacKaye Weiss, titled "The Family and Transition" that includes photographs; "Third Finger, Left Hand"; "Adventuring", "A Full Life"; "End of an Era", "Adventuring in Iran"; "Cruise on the Lao I"; "Cruise on the Lao II"; and "Afghanistan I"
  - Mary L. MacKaye Weiss: Contains the marriage certificate of Arthur MacKaye and Elida Hansen; the..., 1899-1922 (Box 291)
    Mary L. MacKaye Weiss: Contains the marriage certificate of Arthur MacKaye and Elida Hansen; the eleventh volume of Mary Weiss's scrapbook/autobiography entitled "India and Nepal"; scrapbook entitled "The Palo Alto Interlude"; "My Letters: Palo Alto and Thailand" by Mary Weiss; "My Letters: Iran - Lao - Afghanistan" by Mary Weiss; the tenth volume titled "Afghanistan II" of Mary Weiss's scrapbook/autobiography; "My Letters: Libya" by Mary Weiss; "My Letters: After Losing Bud" by Mary Weiss; "Letters: David (After Becky) Including Tonga"; draft copies of passages from Weiss's scrapbook/autobiography; a collection of poems by Robert Keith MacKaye; a draft copy of "The Form and Function of Creation" by David S. MacKaye; and "Letters - David + Family" including correspondence, artwork, and pictures from family members
  - Contains a manuscript of "A Topological Model of Genesis" by David S. MacKaye; a manuscript copy..., 1901-1991 (Box 292)
    Contains a manuscript of "A Topological Model of Genesis" by David S. MacKaye; a manuscript copy of "A limited Flora for An Elegant Planet" by David S. Macaye; "My Biography", David MacKaye's autobiography; a manuscript of the autobiography "Who the Hell is Cloudesley Johns" by Johns; correspondence and miscellaneous writings of David MacKaye; the January/March 1976 issue of The Living Wilderness; photographs; writings; newspaper clippings; the November 30, 1934 issue of the Celtic Forum; "The Lesson of Fire", a set of poems by Robert Keith MacKaye; "The Autobiography of an Idiot" by Jeannie Peet; "The Young MacKayes" consisting of children's artwork and correspondence; and "Letters: Family I", "Letters: Family II", "Letters: Family 3" and "Letters: Family 4", all consisting of MacKaye family correspondence from the 1930's to the 1990's
  - Mary L. MacKaye Weiss: Contains "Letters: Friends I", "Letters: Friends II (And Alone to 1980, O..., 1929-199 (Box 293)
    Mary L. MacKaye Weiss: Contains "Letters: Friends I", "Letters: Friends II (And Alone to 1980, Our Overseas Life)", "Letters: Friends III (After Bud)", and "Letters: Friends IV (1989 and on)", all collections of correspondence with friends 1930-1997; "Letters: Bud", a collection of letters from her husband Bud; "Letters: Fowcett Phillips (Special)"; "Letters and Records - Business I", "Letters and Records - Business II", and "Letters and Records - Business III", containing high school and college diplomas, educational credentials, correspondence about traveling and working abroad, and other materials about the Weiss's public life, including donation of their effects
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains a journal of typewritten writings and supplements on Percy MacKaye's poe..., 1898-1955 (Box 294)
    Percy MacKaye: Contains a journal of typewritten writings and supplements on Percy MacKaye's poetry written by B.A. Botkin, a framed handwritten note, a framed photograph of a cabin, and three letter boxes. The first includes correspondence and publications relating to the recruitment of actors for and general production of Percy MacKaye's 1916 Community Masque of the New York City Shakespeare Tercentenary Celebration, "Caliban by the Yellow Sands." The second contains miscellaneous correspondence and newspaper clippings, as well as materials documenting Percy's writing of a Shakespearean tetralogy, and the third contains miscellaneous correspondence post-1955
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains many small memo books with miscellaneous notes, small cards advertising ..., 1893-1956 (Box 295)
    Percy MacKaye: Contains many small memo books with miscellaneous notes, small cards advertising "Caliban by the Yellow Sands," the paperbound books "Music Shakespeare Loved" and "Books Shakespeare Read," Percy MacKaye's unpublished volume "Poems: 1937-1938," a program from "Caliban," various correspondence regarding Percy MacKaye's work and family, typewritten portions of "The Journal of Marion Morse MacKaye," a publication "Percy MacKaye: A Sketch of his Life with Bibliography of his Works," a publication "A Threefold Greeting to Members of Pan-American Poets' League of North America from Percy MacKaye, President," a series of correspondence to Percy remembering his wife, as well as a folder of newspaper clippings and written tributes from the time of her death, a book "Letters of Percy & Marion: September 18, ‘96- June 17, ‘97," handbound by Percy, copies of Percy's New York Times piece "Albert Steffen's ‘Peace Tragedy' in Switzerland" in both English and German, late nineteenth century correspondence with Percy's father, typewritten pages from "Dr. Oliver Lodge on Personal Immortality," copies of a legal agreement between Percy MacKaye and Arvia MacKaye Ege, and a typewritten draft of "Ten Men of America and the Master Man: Poems of Contemporaneous History" by MacKaye
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains two letter boxes with miscellaneous correspondence, some related to his ..., 1913-1948 (Box 296)
    Percy MacKaye: Contains two letter boxes with miscellaneous correspondence, some related to his playwriting
  - Percy MacKaye Contains an inscribed, blank copy of Edward Gordon Craig's "On the Art of the Thea..., 1939-1955 (Box 297)
    Percy MacKaye Contains an inscribed, blank copy of Edward Gordon Craig's "On the Art of the Theatre," two letter boxes containing various correspondence, a copy of the "Authors League Bulletin," photographs and correspondence of a woman named Maria, a copy of MacKaye's writings "The Faith of Poetry," "Albert Steffen: Poet-Dramatist of Switzerland," and "The Kentucky Mountains," a program of "The Scarecrow," an announcement of "The Mystery of Hamlet, King of Denmark or, What We Will," a program of Percy's 80th birthday, a program of "Caliban," a copy of "The Oxford Criterion" with a piece by MacKaye, performance photographs of "The Mystery of Hamlet, King of Denmark," photographs of MacKaye, his family, and various plays, as well as large transparencies of some performance photographs, and copies of the sheet music to "The Soft Rains Are Falling," with words by MacKaye
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains two letter boxes. One holds newspaper clippings related to Percy MacKaye..., 1924-1959 (Box 298)
    Percy MacKaye: Contains two letter boxes. One holds newspaper clippings related to Percy MacKaye, a letter to the editor written by MacKaye to the New York Times, typewritten versions of his poetry, a letter written to his children about his relationship with his wife, biographical information written by MacKaye to be inserted in "Old New York Families," information concerning MacKaye for inclusion in the "Biographical Encyclopedia of the World," excerpts from "Epoch: The Life of Steele MacKaye," and various correspondence. The other holds an open letter to Jane Austen concerning a play, and various handwritten and typewritten poetry
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains folders of memorial letters written for Marion Morse MacKaye, several co..., 1914-1955 (Box 299)
    Percy MacKaye: Contains folders of memorial letters written for Marion Morse MacKaye, several copies of "The Trees of Harvard," a dedicatory poem read by Percy MacKaye at the Quindecennial Celebration of the Harvard Class of 1897, "Facing Infinitude," a publication by Marion Morse MacKaye in her memory, a program "Golden Wedding of Marion Morse and Percy MacKaye," and "For the Friends of Marion & Percy MacKaye," a typewritten piece "The Supernatural in Shakespeare" by Maria Iannella, the first letter written from Maria to Percy, and two letter boxes. These contain newspaper clippings about a pageant and masque in St. Louis, National Arts Club bulletins, and materials from Percy's eightieth birthday party, including guest lists, related correspondence, and newspaper clippings
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains framed and unframed photographs of Marion Morse MacKaye and a framed Val..., 1883-1956 (Box 300)
    Percy MacKaye: Contains framed and unframed photographs of Marion Morse MacKaye and a framed Valentine's Day letter from the same, nineteenth century family photographs, including some of William MacKaye, photocopies of Will's drawings, and two letter boxes. One contains letters addressed to Mrs. Arvia MacKaye Ege at the time of her father, Percy's, death, a copy of a "New Yorker" magazine with a poem by Percy, and typewritten obituary materials, some in German. The other contains miscellaneous correspondence
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains letters written from Percy to his children (primarily Arvia), a play "..., 1899-1956 (Box 301)
    Percy MacKaye: Contains letters written from Percy to his children (primarily Arvia), a play "The Love Potion," by Marion Morse MacKaye, a binder of typewritten poems by Percy, sheet music for "The Soft Rains are Falling" (words by Percy), photocopied material on the Cornish Colony, material related to the Morse genealogy, including a poem written while one family member was a sophomore at Dartmouth, photographs of Percy and family, a notebook of Percy's containing poetry, several copies of "Marion Morse MacKaye, A Comment: For her Seventieth Birthday Celebration..." written by Percy, correspondence with Gordon Craig, a music book "Choruses of Caliban" (words by Percy), "Chronicles of the Cottage" written for her children by Mary Medbery MacKaye, poems written by Percy to Arvia, a copy of "The New Yorker" with a poem by Percy, a copy of "The Churchman" magazine, a copy of "Mark Twain Quarterly," and a plaster mask
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains typewritten poetry by Percy MacKaye, and Robert Keith MacKaye, correspon..., 1927-1991 (Box 302)
    Percy MacKaye: Contains typewritten poetry by Percy MacKaye, and Robert Keith MacKaye, correspondence between Percy's daughter Christy and John Edsall, publicity materials for Percy and his plays, a program of Percy's poems to be read by Christy at an event, photographs of Percy, a "Classes of ‘97" publication containing "Stanzas by Percy MacKaye for the Fiftieth Reunion of the Harvard Class of 1897," a floppy disk of "MacKaye Poems" and one of Robert Keith (Robin) MacKaye's "Lesson of Fire," and various correspondence
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains a typewritten version of Marion Morse MacKaye's diary, correspondence be..., 1898-1918 (Box 303)
    Percy MacKaye: Contains a typewritten version of Marion Morse MacKaye's diary, correspondence between Percy and Madeline Bedell concerning the preparation of a bound volume of his wife's diary, a box of family photographs, and a copy of "Stars and Atoms Have No Size: Poems of Science and Industry" by A.M. Sullivan
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains bound collections of Percy MacKaye's poetry and other writing, press no..., 1879-1965 (Box 304)
    Percy MacKaye: Contains bound collections of Percy MacKaye's poetry and other writing, press notices for "Caliban" and other masques, and lectures. Also contains a bound collection "The Writing of William Payson MacKaye," "William Payson MacKaye: Letters, 1879-1888," "James Steele MacKaye's Adaptation of the Delsarte System of Expression for the Spectatorium," and loose letters from Percy to his daughter Arvia
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains portions of the diary of Marion Morse MacKaye and three letter boxes. Th..., 1914-1920 (Box 305)
    Percy MacKaye: Contains portions of the diary of Marion Morse MacKaye and three letter boxes. These contain several copies of "Who's Who in Pageantry," several copies of "Hazel MacKaye: Her Work in Community Drama," a publication "It Happens in Japan" from The Womens Press, a publication "A Community Welfare Week" by William Lloyd Davis, various newspaper clippings concerning woman suffrage, Hazel's correspondence with the Congressional Union for Woman Suffrage and National Woman's Party, several copies of "Blue Triangle News," a large amount of family photographs, and writing and correspondence of Arvia MacKaye
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains four bound collections of Percy MacKaye's poetry, a book "Chief Contempo..., 1890-1951 (Box 306)
    Percy MacKaye: Contains four bound collections of Percy MacKaye's poetry, a book "Chief Contemporary Dramatists" by Thomas H. Dickinson, a notebook of Percy's, "Some Early A.T. History" by Benton MacKaye, several written pieces by Mary Medbery MacKaye, including "A Brief Sketch of the Life of Rebecca Belnap Stetson Medbery," "The Civic Theatre: Suggestions Regarding its Scope and Organization" by Percy MacKaye, "Lucinda's Whim" by Harold Steele MacKaye, a program for the Harvard Dramatic Club's "The Scarecrow" by Percy MacKaye, a copy of Shakespear's "Macbeth," a journal containing handwritten notes, and various correspondence and small publications
  - Percy MacKaye: Contains three bound collections of Percy MacKaye's poetry, as well as some loose..., 1899-1953 (Box 307)